## **Svechnikov Gleb**

Engineer, Designer, UI Developer

Phone: +995591339765

Email: gleb.svechnikov@gmail.com

Date of birth: 06/08/1987

Current location: Tbilisi, Georgia

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/glebsvechnikov/



# **Objectives**

I'm a UI developer with a big **focus on design** in general, not only Web or Graphical, but also Service Design, Product design and Industrial Design. Combination of my scientific oriented mind and good communication skills helps me to find common language between technology people and business people in order to create the best solution for the end user.

Working as a developer for more than 15 years I came to a conclusion that most problems in product development occur not on the technology side, but rather in a gap between technology and design. And the solution I see and used to solve this gap is a design system and continuous improvement in communication between these two sides.

## **Experience**

Infoculture Senior frontend developer	06/2021 - present
Siemens UI developer	11/2021 - 06/2022
Simplinic Lead UI developer	08/2018 - 05/2021
Intermedia UI developer, team lead(since 2017)	07/2013 - 08/2018
Dnevnik.ru Frontend development	08/2012 - 07/2013
Independent freelance developer Web development, web consulting	Since 2007
Yallee Srl, Milan Frontend web developer	07/2011 - 02/2012
TV Blob, Milan AJAX developer	02/2011 - 05/2011
Department of Automation Systems, MIREA, Moscow Researcher, Teacher Assistant	09/2007 - 07/2008
Department of Electrotechnics, MIREA, Moscow Researcher, Hardware developer	04/2006 - 07/2007
Research Institute of Automatic Equipment, Moscow Research fellow, Junior System Administrator (FreeBSD)	09/2004 - 12/2005

## **Academical achievements**

In September 2009 I've organized conference in MIREA called "New technologies for education and science"

In January 2012 I've published a book in Lambert Academic Publishing, a monograph called "<u>Informational-Educational system for knowledge management in University</u>" and it's based on my thesis which I've presented in Russia in March 2011.

In 2014 as my final project for Game Changes track Transforming Education I've created math class(extracurricular) for children (10-14 years). I've adopted Computer-based Math methodology and Open Source solutions. First year taught in Presidential Physics and Mathematics Lyceum №239 and second year taught in private school DigitalBanana sponsored by JetBrains.

### **Education**

#### **Game Changes ed-hoc education**(Saint-Petersburg)

- 2013 Transforming education track
- 2014 Neuroscience and education track

#### Politecnico di Milano, Master of Computer Science in Communication

Politecnico di Milano, Como campus 2008 - 2012(completed all exams, have not presented thesis)

#### Computer engineering, Specialist in Informatics and management in technical systems

Moscow State University of Radioengineering, Electronics and Automation, Faculty of Cybernetics 2005 - 2011

### **Trainings**

- Flutter & Dart The Complete Guide, Udemy 2021
- The Road to React by Robin Wieruch, 2018
- Beginners guide to elm programming: build web apps on Udemy, 2017
- Development with Meteor on Coursera, 2016
- Functional programming with LISP on Hexlet, 2015
- TFS project management training from Scrum School, 2014
- Udacity, Web application Engineering
   Web development with Python and Google App Engine, currently
- Net tuts+, jQuery
   Javascript programing with jQuery library, March 2011
- Code Academy
   Javascript and web programing, 2011
- Cisco Academy in MIREA, Cisco Certified Network Associate (CCNA) Networking, 2008

Constantly follow web standards, frontend and design news and technologies via RSS, podcasts, blogs, videos and articles.

#### Languages

- English, business level
- **Italian**, intermediate level
- Russian, native speaker

#### **General skills**

- International Driving License (B)
- Sufficient experience in international communication
- Relational and critical thinking

### Computer skills and competences

- Programming languages: Python, C# in ASP.NET, JS/ECMAScript
- Domain Specific Languages: LESS, TypeScript
- Web: HTML5, CSS3, SVG
- Libraries: jQuery, React, Luxon, Lodash, D3, Highcharts
- Frameworks: Vue, AngularJS/Angular, MeteorJS
- Version control systems: Git(Github/Gitlab/Bitbucket), SVN, TFS
- Task runners: Grunt, Gulp, Webpack
- Package management: NPM, PyPI
- CMS and frameworks: Drupal, Joomla, Wordpress, Django, Moodle
- Task management: Jira, Podio, Clarizen, Asana
- e-documentation systems: Google Drive, MediaWiki, DokuWiki, Confluence, Notion
- Containers and virtualization: Docker, Kubernetes, Vagrant
- Graphic editors: Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, XD; Gimp,Inkscape; Figma